ABOUT ME

While I'm a proficient fullstack developer able to work on front-end and testing code, my expertise lies is building scalable back-end services in .Net with the best practices and performance always in mind.

Being challenged and working on something that really gets me out of comfort zone is all that I'm about. Further more, continuously learning new development techniques and practices that is or will be important to me and the success of the organization is mandatory to me.

Contact Info

Mobile 57816194

Email FarazPoomun2k@gmail.com

FARAZ **POOMUN**

Full-Stack Sr. Software Developer

20 Maurice Poupard ST, Plaine-Verte Port-Louis

Portfolio %

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mauricall International Ltd

(Aug 2015 - Jan 2017)

Customer Support

Major responsibilities included assisting clients via telephone/chat and emails with queries pertaining the company's application

Ceridian Mauritius Ltd

(Jun 2018 - Nov 2018)

Internship

Using .NET framework, redesigned and refactored Ceridian's internal tool UI. Also underwent multiple training to improve soft skills and technical skills

Ceridian Mauritius Ltd (2019 - Ongoing)

Full-Stack Software Developer

- Triaged and fixed internal/client bugs
- Worked on designing backend structures following appropriate pattern to implement or enhance features
- Worked closely with product management to define and design requirements
- Upskill the team, through constant learning and sharing the knowledge with team members
- Greatly contributed to improving the team's
- Enforces standard and code quality through code review

Ceridian Learning Centre

(2021 - Ongoing)

.Net/C# Trainer

Have been training interns/freshers/postgraduate students on C#, Clean code, and best practices

Objectivity (Part of Accenture)

(2023 - Ongoing)

Full-Stack Sr. Software Developer

- Triaged and fixed internal/client bugs
- Worked on designing backend structures following appropriate pattern to implement or enhance feature
- Enforces standard and code quality through code review

Social Links



Technical Stack

- C#/.Net
- MVC framework
- SQL
- Gherkin
- NUnit
- NoSQL(MongoDB)

- HTML/CSS/JS/TS
- GIT
- Getting started with Azure
- D0J0
- React

Skills

- Knowledgeable of back-end developing best practices
- Possess the ability to have an impact in a team
- Constant drive to learn and share my knowledge
- Able to work at flexible hours
- Able to adapt to the ever-changing software development environment
- Good communication skills
- Familiar and at east with the Agile methodology

Education

Zakariyya Muslim School (2006 – 2014)

University Of Mauritius (2016 – 2019)

Higher School Certificate

- BSc (Hons) Software Engineering
 - Graduated with 1st Class Honors
 - Won the inter-Cohort debate during first year

Achievements

- Optimized SQL queries, backend processing for better code performance
- Created internal tools to assist developers in their day-to-day tasks
- Been the subject-matter expert (SME) of various areas within the team
- Good understanding of various backend design patterns
- Able to do code testing via NUnit, Mog and Automation via Gherkin
- Worked with and have a proper understanding of the version control Git
- Azure AZ-900 certified